Guide to the Stetson and Minor Family Photographs Collection, 1862 - 1948
Stetson and Minor Family Photographs Collection, 1862 - 1948
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Stetson family.
Minor family.
1000-129
0.5
1
Willis Kimball Stetson, son of Daniel Kimball Stetson and Mary Weeks Sanborn Stetson, born 1858 and died 1942. After graduating from Wesleyan University, Class of 1881, he taught public school in Ansonia, CT then became the Assistant Librarian and Librarian at Wesleyan University from 1882 to 1887. Willis Kimball Stetson married Lillian Minor and had three children: John Minor Stetson (born 1887), George Albert Stetson (born 1889) and Mary Mead Stetson (born 1891). Margaret Buell Allen is the daughter of Frederick G. and Mary Mead Stetson Allen. There is no accompanying biographical information regarding the Minor family photographs or other Stetson family member photographs.
This collection contains a three generation history in photographs of the Minor and Stetson families from 1862-1948.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisitions Information
Received circa 1982 from R.W. Clarke, Class of 1921.
Biographical Note
Willis Kimball Stetson, son of Daniel Kimball Stetson and Mary Weeks Sanborn Stetson, born 1858 and died 1942. After graduating from Wesleyan University, Class of 1881, he taught public school in Ansonia, CT then became the Assistant Librarian and Librarian at Wesleyan University from 1882 to 1887. Willis Kimball Stetson married Lillian Minor and had three children: John Minor Stetson (born 1887), George Albert Stetson (born 1889) and Mary Mead Stetson (born 1891). Margaret Buell Allen is the daughter of Frederick G. and Mary Mead Stetson Allen. There is no accompanying biographical information regarding the Minor family photographs or other Stetson family member photographs.
Collection Overview
This collection contains a three generation history in photographs of the Minor and Stetson families from 1862-1948; Willis Kimball Stanton, his father Daniel K. Stetson and his children John Minor, George Albert and Mary Mead.
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Stetson family.; Minor family.; Photographs.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.) --Alumni and alumnae.
Detailed Description of the Collection
  - Allen, Margaret Buell (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Grandma McCall. Hannah Stowe Sullivan (John Minor's Mother?) (Folder 2)
  - Minor, Alla Mead, nine photos, only one photo dated January 13, 1862 (Folder 3)
  - Minor, George S. (Folder 4)
  - Minor, Georgianna (Folder 5)
  - Minor, John A.one photo in folder dated Jan. 13, 1862 (Folder 6)
  - Stetson, Daniel Kimball and Mary Weeks Sanborn Stetson (Mrs. D.K. Stetson) and photos of their home in Pasadena, CA with thousands of roses in the garden. (Folder 7)
  - Stetson, George Albert and his siblings John M. Stetson and Mary Mead Stetson (Allen) through childhood. The first photo is George Albert Stetson c. 1887 at 3 months. (Folder 8)
  - Dr. George A. Stetson, obituary
  - George A. Stetson, c.1907, high school graduation?
  - George A. Stetson, c. 1910, graduated from Yale Sheffield Scientific (?) 1910
  - George A. Stetson, undated
  - George A. Stetson, 1948, receiving Honorary degree from Stevens Institute of Technology
  - Minor, Solomon Miller (Folder 9)
  - Minor, Urania Foster Treat (Folder 10)
  - Stetson, Lillian Alla Minor at various ages, beginning at infancy. Photo of a group of women that consists of Lillian M. Stetson, Sally Stetson, Georgianna Minor and Alla Minor. (Folder 11)
  - Stetson, Margaret Atwater (Folder 12)
  - Stetson, Willis Kimball, May 8, 1938 his 80th birthday and earlier photographs. (Folder 13)
  - Unidentified photographs from the Stetson and Minor collection. (Folder 14)
  - Photograph of early Minor House (Folder 15)
  - Stetson Kindred of America (Inc.): Brief Sketch of Work of Organization and Extended Account of Second Reunion, Held August 18, 1906
  - Third Reunion and Annual Meeting Stetson Kindred of America (Inc.), Medford, MA, August 1, 1907
  - Honor Tucker Stetson, copy of talk presented at Stetson Kindred of America, 1954 Reunion
  - The Meeting House and the Puritan Tradition, by William Coughlan, President of the Abington Historical Society, copy of talk presented at Stetson Kindred of America, 1954 Reunion
  - The Stetson Coat-of-Arms, copy of talk presented at Stetson Kindred of America, 1954 Reunion
  - 3 page description of photographs